Review Exercise L. Three-Word Phrase Story. The Amazing Rock Soup. A tired
young hiker was striding through the thick dark forest when he came upon a gnarled
old crone standing before a small stone hut in a sunny little clearing. My poor
old stomach is really very empty, he thought. I hope the old landlady can spare
a little food. Sensing what he was about to say, she snapped, No, I have barely
enough for myself. My good woman, he said, on the contrary. I'd like to cook you a
sumptuously rich dinner of rock soup. She was naturally very suspicious, but she let
him in. He boiled some clear fresh water, added three clean rocks, and hung the
dented old kettle in the old fireplace.
He tasted the mysterious liquid concoction. This is truly very delicious,
he declared, but it would be so much better with just one little vegetable. She
begrudgingly gave him a small-limb carrot and two dry onions. Yum, he said happily,
but if only. Bit by bit, he cajoled the lonely housewife into making a savory stew
pot. The two of them sat down, smiled at each other, and enjoyed a fabulous dinner
together.